（春野はるのサクラ）だああ～！
（うずまきナルト）おっ
あっ
We're too late...
（はたけカカシ）遅かったか
Sasori...
（チヨ）サソリ…
Neji...
（マイト･ガイ）ネジ
俺の状況は見えているか？
Can you see what's happening
to me here?
（日向ひゅうがネジ）ああ
Yeah...
The same thing is happening here.
こっちも同じ状況だ
Tenten, what about you?
（ガイ）テンテン そっちは？
It's probably...
the same here, too.
（テンテン）たぶん同じ状況
Lee!
（ガイ）リー？
（ロック･リー）
札を剥がしたとたんに
森の中に怪しい影が出現しました
A strange shadow appeared in the forest
as soon as I removed the tag.
I thought so...
やはり そうか
Team Kakashi has infiltrated
just as planned.
（ネジ）カカシ班は
予定どおり中に侵入した
What is...this...?
なんなの？ これ
It's probably an enemy trap.
恐らく敵のトラップでしょう
I see...
なるほど
そういうわけね
So that's what this is about.
相手にとって不足なしです
I find you a worthy opponent.
♪～
～♪
Traps Activate!
Team Guy's Enemies
くっ… てめえ
You jerk...!
くっ…
どこ座ってんだよ！
Where do you think you're sitting?!
（デイダラ）フッ
間違いないな うん
No doubt about it...
あいつが人柱力だ
He's the Jinchuriki.
“最初に大声で
どなってくるヤツ”か…
"The first one to yell and
scream at you," huh?
イタチのヤツ
特徴 教えんのうめえな うん
Itachi's pretty good
at describing people.
（チヨ）サソリ…
Sasori...
（ナルト）我愛羅があら！
Gaara!
そんなところで
何 のんきに寝てんだってばよ
What're you doing sleeping leisurely
in a place like that?!
立てよ
Stand up!
Gaara!
我愛羅！
おい 我愛羅 聞いてんのか？
Hey! Gaara! Are you listening?!
いいかげんにしろよ！
Knock it off!
（カカシ）やめろ ナルト！
（ナルト）くっ…
That's enough, Naruto!
（カカシ）分かってるはずだ
You should know...
（ナルト）くっ…
そうそう 分かってんだろ？
That's right. You know, don't you?
とっくに死んでるってな うん？
That he's already long dead.
（サソリ）ほ～
Oh...
確かに人柱力だな うん
He's definitely...the Jinchuriki.
（サクラ）あっ
（ナルト）返せ
Give him back...
我愛羅を返せ この野郎が！
Give Gaara back!
You jerks!
はっ！
（カカシ）落ち着け
考えなしに突っ込めば全滅だ
Calm down...
If you charge ahead without thinking,
we'll be annihilated.
くっ…
忍の活動はスリーマンセル
もしくはフォーマンセルが基本だ
A Shinobi usually operates
in a three-man squad
or a four-man squad.
（ネジ）だが 五封結界を破るには
最低でも５人は必要
But at least five people are required
to destroy a Five-Seal Barrier.
１班だけでは
破ることができない
It can't be destroyed with
just one team.
どうしても もう１班の到着を
待たなければならない
You'd have to wait for
another team to arrive.
五封結界を張ったというだけで
Just putting up a Five-Seal Barrier
should serve as a means for stalling...
すでに足止めに
なっているわけですね
（ガイ）さらに結界が外されても
In addition, it's configured
so that a trap activates when
the barrier is removed.
トラップが発動する
仕組みになっている
Namely, a copy of the person who
removes the tag appears nearby.
（ネジ）すなわち札を剥がした者の
コピーが近くに現れ
はあっ
結界への侵入を阻むってわけね
They're preventing us from making
our way through the barrier, huh?
（リー）つまり
自分自身を倒さぬ限り
In other words...
we can't go back up to
Naruto and the others
ナルト君たちの援護には行けない
ということですか？
unless we defeat ourselves...
Is that how this works?
（ガイ）そのとおりだ リーよ
Exactly, Lee.
フォーマンセルをばらして
１人ずつにし
They break up the four-man squad
and separate us individually.
結界には周到に
保険までかけてるとは
And even taking precaution by placing
a back-up on the barrier...
大したやつらだ
They're quite impressive.
でも 感心ばかりも
してられないのよね
But...we can't just sit here
acting impressed.
いざ 勝負です
Now, let's fight!
ああーっ！
あっ…
ああっ
さすがは俺の偽物 やるな
I'd expect no less from my fake!
He's pretty good.
（ネジ）あっ
（ネジ）姿だけでなく力も同じか
They don't just look the same...
They've got the same power too, huh...?
はあっ！
ハア ハア…
装備も同じと考えていいわね
We should consider them as having
the same weapons too, huh...?
（リー）何から何まで
同じというわけですか
So basically everything about them
is the same, huh?
ますます 戦い甲斐がありますね
This makes them even
more worthwhile opponents, eh?!
くっ うう…
うん？ どうした サソリの旦那
What is it, Sasori my man?
（サソリ）そいつは俺が預かる
I'll  take him.
（デイダラ）はっ？
（サソリ）どうやら あの人柱力は
こいつを取り返したいらしいからな
It seems that Jinchuriki wants
to take him back, so...
うん そうみたいだな
It seems so.
（カカシ）どうやら
左側が単身 砂に乗り込み...
It appears the guy on the left
is the one who infiltrated
the Sand alone and took Gaara.
風影様を連れ去った
ヤツのようだな
すると こっちが
Which means this guy's...
カンクロウ君に
深手を負わせた傀儡くぐつ師
the Puppet Master who
seriously injured Kankuro...
彼女の孫のサソリか
Her grandson Sasori, huh?
My man...
（デイダラ）旦那？
（サソリ）うん？
これを言ったら
たぶん旦那は怒るだろうけどよ
You'll probably get mad if I say this...
あの人柱力は
おいらがやる うん
But I'll  take care
of that Jinchuriki.
（サソリ）んっ…
Our mission is one Jinchuriki each.
ノルマは１人１匹だろうが
図に乗るなよ デイダラ
Don't be getting all full
of yourself, Deidara...
（デイダラ）芸術家ってのは
より強い刺激を求めていねえと
An artist's passion starts to dull
unless they seek
greater stimulation, my man...
感情が鈍っちまうもん
なんすよ 旦那
九尾の人柱力は
なかなかに強いって噂だしな うん
The rumor is the Nine-Tailed Jinchuriki
is quite powerful.
おいらの芸術に
ふさわしい相手だ うん
He's an opponent suitable for my art.
（サソリ）なんだ？
あの爆発が芸術だってのか
What? You're calling those explosions
of yours art?
Art is something that beautifully remains...
芸術ってのは長く美しく
あとあとまで残っていくもの
extensively into the distant future.
永久の美こそが芸術だ
Eternal beauty is art!
Eternal beauty...is art?
（デイダラ）永久の美が芸術？
（デイダラ）同じモノづくりとして
旦那 あんたは尊敬するが
I do respect you as
a fellow craftsman, my man.
But art is a fleeting moment of beauty
that vanishes gloriously.
芸術ってのは...
美しく儚く散っていく
一瞬の美をいうんだよ うん
What did you say...?
（サソリ）なんだと？
Wh-What's up with...these guys?
な… なんなの？ こいつら
Deidara, it seems you don't
understand what true art is...
（サソリ）デイダラ
お前は本当の芸術ってもんが
分かってないようだな
You're  the one
who doesn't understand.
（デイダラ）
それは旦那のほうだろ うん？
（ナルト）てめえら…
You jerks...!
（サソリ）いいや
永久の美こそ本当の芸術だ
No! Eternal beauty is true art.
Don't be a fool.
Art is an instant of beauty.
（デイダラ）バカ言っちゃいけねえ
芸術は 一瞬の美だ
（ナルト）ふざけやがって！
Knock it off!
あっ
（サソリ）てめえは
俺を怒らせてえのか？
Do you want to make me angry?
I just told you...
だから
It would probably make
you angry, didn't I...?
“たぶん怒るだろうけど”って
さっき言ったろうが うん？
（サソリ）俺を怒らせると
どういうことになるか...
You know what happens
when I get angry, don't you?
分かってんだろうな
He blocked the shuriken
without looking at all...
（サクラ）少しも見ずに手裏剣を…
He's just as good with
the Puppet Master technique
（チヨ）やはり 傀儡さばきは
昔のままじゃな
as he always was.
How about it, Deidara?
（サソリ）どうなんだ？ デイダラ
（デイダラ）フッ
Art to me is...
おいらにとっての芸術とは…
explosiveness itself!
爆発 そのものだ
うん！
ああ…
It's a far cry from
your silly puppet shows!
旦那のびっくり人形劇とは
わけが違うぜ うん
（サソリ）チッ
See you around, my man!
じゃあな 旦那
Make sure you follow me,
Nine-Tailed Jinchuriki...
（デイダラ）ちゃんとついてこいよ
九尾の人柱力
くっ… えいっ
（カカシ）はっ
（サクラ）あっ
That jerk Deidara
is doing as he pleases...
（サソリ）デイダラめ
勝手なまねを…
待て こら！
Hey, wait!
All right.
（デイダラ）よし
Naruto!
（カカシ）ナルト！
（カカシ）チッ… ナルトのやつ
やはり止まらないか
I guess Naruto won't stop, will he?
Naruto and I will take care
of the guy outside.
（カカシ）ナルトと俺は
外のヤツをやる
Sakura and Granny Chiyo...
you two handle the guy inside.
サクラとチヨバア様は
中のこいつを…
However...
ただし ガイ班が戻ってくるまで
make sure you don't do
anything rash until Team Guy gets back.
くれぐれも
むちゃはしないように
うん 分かった
Got it.
（デイダラ）うん？
フッ あいつも来たのか
He came too, huh...?
Guy, can you hear me?
（カカシ）ガイ 聞こえるか？
The enemy has split up.
We need backup.
敵が二手に分かれた
援護が必要だ
今すぐ戻ってくれ
Return immediately.
（ガイ）ハア…
それが そうもいかんのだ
I don't think we can.
（カカシ）ん…
ハア… 皆
敵のワナに はまった
We've all been caught
in an enemy trap.
Kakashi, give us a little more time.
カカシ もう少し時間をくれ
あっ…
切るぞ
Signing off!
どわーっ！
（ガイ）くっ この動き…
These movements...
We're an even match, huh?
互角か…
I can't believe they look the same,
have the same power
（ネジ）同じ姿 同じ力
使ってくる術まで同じとは…
and even use the same Jutsu...
（テンテン）ええいっ
It's just like fighting our mirror images...
まるで鏡に映った自分と
戦ってるみたい
If it were mirrors,
we only need to break it, but...
鏡なら割れば おしまいですが…
木こノ葉は旋風せんぷう！
Leaf Hurricane!
It doesn't look like
they'll be easily broken.
簡単に割れそうもありませんね
Give Gaara back!
我愛羅を返しやがれ！
（デイダラ）フッ
Looks like...
（カカシ）こりゃあ…
チンタラしてられないな
I can't be wasting my time...
（サソリ）ハア～
とっくの昔に引退したと
聞いていたんだがな
I'd heard that you'd retired long ago.
I suddenly wanted to see
my grandson's face again.
（チヨ）急に
孫の顔が見たくなってな
（サクラ）はっ
I can tell just by facing him.
対峙しただけで分かる
The incredible difference
in actual battle experience...
ものすごい実戦経験の差と
人を殺してきた数
and the number of people he's killed.
（サクラ）ん…
サクラ 恐れるな
Sakura, do not fear.
I'm here. You step back.
このわしがおる
お前は後ろへ下がっておれ
Assault Blade.
操襲刃そうしゅうは
If you're going to defy me,
then I guess I have no choice...
（サソリ）俺に たてつこうってんなら
しかたねえ
Will you join that kid
そこのガキと 一緒に
俺のコレクションになるか？
as additions to my collection,
Grandma Chiyo?
チヨバアよ
♪～
～♪
Only one event remains for
the World Puppet Master Championship!
全国傀儡王選手権
残された競技もあと１つ
Will the proud title of
fi
栄えある初代 傀儡王に輝くのは
第１ステージ 古今東西 毒クイズで
トップ通過を果たした...
天才造形師 赤砂のサソリか
はたまた 第２ステージ
傀儡早作り勝負で
長年の経験と技を見せつけた
砂の相談役 チヨバアか
最終ステージ 傀儡戦
果たして勝敗は？
次回「ヒルコＶＳバーサス
二人の女忍者くのいち」
（ネジ）木ノ葉 一族図鑑 第２巻
第２巻は うちは一族についてだ
（リー）うお～！ それは楽しみです
（ネジ）写輪眼(しゃりんがん)をはじめ
ずば抜けた能力を持つ うちは一族
中でも火遁かとん忍術を得意とし
火を操るうちわを持つ者として
一族の家紋にうちわを用いている
彼らが里の治安を守るために
組織したのが
木ノ葉刑務部隊だ
（リー）忍を取り締まる忍
まさにエリートですね
（ネジ）また この南賀ノ(なかの)神社には
うちは一族の秘密が眠っている
とも言われている
もしかしたら
イタチやサスケの里抜けとも
何か関係があるかもしれないな
うちはには
まだまだ謎が多いですね
いずれにせよ イタチのいる暁あかつきや
大蛇丸おろちまるとやりあうために
俺たちは今以上に
強くならなければならない
（ネジ）そのために…
（リー）そのためにも
まずは修業です
おい リー 何をする？
（リー）いきますよ～
（ネジ）あっ おろせって
（リー）青春パワー…
（ネジ）
青春って暑苦しい